Guide to the Lynn Riggs Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lynn Riggs papers
1924-1954
YCAL MSS 61
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
14.25
(32 boxes)
The Lynn Riggs Papers consist of letters, manuscripts, photographs, financial and legal documents and printed materials relating to the life and work of Riggs and his associates such as Ramon Naya and George O'Neil.
Riggs, Lynn, 1899-1954
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were donated by Lynn Riggs' literary agent, Lucy Kroll, in 1984.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
LYNN RIGGS (1899-1954)
Rollie Lynn Riggs was born in northeast Indian Territory [now Oklahoma] on August 31, 1899 to William Grant Riggs, a rancher and banker, and Rose Ella Buster Gills Riggs. After his mother died in 1901, several members of the Riggs family aided in raising Lynn and his two siblings. He was educated at the Eastern University Preparatory School in Claremore before taking off to seek his fortune at age 17 in Chicago and Los Angeles. At 21, he returned home to enroll in the University of Oklahoma, financing his education by mortgaging a small acreage which had been allotted to him by virtue of his mother's Cherokee Indian ancestry.
Riggs left school in the middle of his final year and at the suggestion of friends, he made his way to Santa Fe, New Mexico, where he sought to recover his health at Sunmount Sanatorium. His crisis soon turned to be a deciding event in his life, for in Santa Fe, he found a community of artists who nurtured his nascent desire to write. His first major production, of the one-act play, Knives from Syria, was mounted by the Santa Fe Players in 1924. He soon dedicated himself to play-writing, writing his first major play, Big Lake, while teaching English at the Lewis Institute in Chicago.
Big Lake was produced in New York, where Riggs moved in 1926 to continue his development as a playwright. The next two years saw his completion and the successful production of several plays, including, Sump'n Like Wings, A Lantern to See By, and Rancor, all of which expounded on memories of growing up in Oklahoma. In 1928, to add to his successes, Lynn Riggs was awarded a John Simon Guggenheim Fellowship to continue his playwriting. The following year was spent travelling throughout Europe, visiting regional theaters and constructing what would become his greatest success, Green Grow the Lilacs.
Upon his return to the United States in 1929, his play Roadside was produced, and the Theatre Guild began negotiations to stage Green Grow the Lilacs. This newest play became a hit in early 1931, setting up Riggs as a writer much-in-demand. The next decade would have Riggs leading a more secure, if scattered existence. He built a house in Santa Fe, though lived for periods in Los Angeles and New York. While working on new works for the stage, he served as a screenwriter for Paramount and Universal Studios, co-authoring such films as Garden of Allah, and The Plainsman. His social circle widened as well. Among his close friends in Hollywood were Bette Davis, Joan Crawford and Franchot Tone, who had played the role of Curly in the original New York production of Green Grow the Lilacs.
Though Riggs continued to write through the 1940s, he focused his energy on other activities. In 1941, he taught a course, "Drama and the Playwright," at Baylor University. From 1942-44, he served in the U.S. military, eventually scripting documentary films for the Office of War Information. It was while he was still enlisted that Oklahoma!, the Pulitzer-citation winning musical version of Green Grow the Lilacs, debuted. Though this beloved staple of the American stage would prosper for years, Riggs found it difficult to mount successful runs of his new works, which focused on more contemporary events in his life, such as his experiences in Santa Fe, as detailed in Laughter From A Cloud.
Riggs worked slowly through the 1950s, creating a historical drama for Western Reserve University, publishing a short story, "Eben, The Hound, and the Hare" in 1952, and working on a novel set in Oklahoma. Though he lived principally on Shelter Island, New York, he travelled often to Chapel Hill to work on projects. His health began to deteriorate after his 50th birthday and he eventually found himself plagued by stomach problems. The full extent of his medical condition was revealed in Spring of 1954, when he was found to have cancer. He died on June 29 of that year in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The Lynn Riggs Papers consist of letters, manuscripts, photographs, legal and financial documents and printed materials concerning the life and work of the playwright. The papers span the years 1924-54, and complement those in the Lynn Riggs Memorial in Claremore, Oklahoma.
The collection is housed in 31 boxes and consists of six series, Correspondence, Writings, Personal Papers, Financial and Legal Papers, Photographs, and Printed Material. Box 31 contains Oversize material.
Series I, Correspondence, contains letters exchanged between Lynn Riggs and many of his friends and collaborators. A significant body of correspondence with Barrett Clark and Garrett Leverton, both during their tenures with Samuel French, Inc. and after, has been preserved. Also included here are letters from Aaron Copland, Sawyer Falk, Andrius Jilinsky, and Sidney Lumet as well as from the directors of theatre groups such as the Hedgerow Theatre and the Theatre Guild. Riggs' professional life is documented in correspondence with his agents, H. E. Edington-F. W. Vincent, Inc. and Lucy Kroll. Among the playwrights, friends, and family included here are Joan Crawford, Bette Davis, Ida Rauh Eastman, Spud Johnson, Witter Bynner, José Limón, Ramon Naya, and Ann Webster. At the end of this series is a group of letters between third parties.
Series II, Writings, is the largest of the series, containing a variety of manuscripts, but concentrating on drafts of Riggs' plays. Among the extant journals are an early notebook from Riggs' first stay in Santa Fe in 1924, and a later private journal dating from 1939-52. Riggs' novel, The Affair at Easter, which he left uncompleted at the time of his death in 1954 is preserved in several fragments.
Of the play manuscripts included here, the majority are drafts of later works which remained in the hands of Riggs' agent, Lucy Kroll, after his death. Among these are the stageplays, All the Way Home (a revision of Verdigris Primitive ), Borned in Texas, (a revision of Roadside ), The Cream in the Well, Hang on to Love, (a revision of Domino Parlor ), Laughter From a Cloud, Out of Dust, and Tragic Ground, an adaptation of the novel by Erskine Caldwell. The only materials concerning Green Grow the Lilacs are notes by Riggs and watercolor sketches by Sidney Lumet for a production of the show. In the 1950s, Riggs worked on several plays for television, such as the two preserved here in different versions, Some Sweet Day (or The Boy with Tyford Fever ), Song in the A.M., and Someone to Remember. Among other projects represented here are a radio play written in conjunction with Ramon Naya, The Cow in the Trailer, a benefit show for the Soldiers Service Club written with William Saroyan, The Gay Nineties, and Origin: Oedipus, a version of a dance drama written in 1947.
Lynn Riggs' poems, housed in the next subseries, show a different aspect of the playwright's art. He published verse as early as the 1920s in various little magazines, but after the publication of The Iron Dish in 1930, poetry became more of an avocation in light of his successes on stage. The poems included here are mostly drafts written in the late 1940s and 1950s.
Riggs' brief career as a screenwriter in the mid-1930s is documented by several drafts included in this archive. Among these are the shooting script of A Day in Santa Fe, a movie he made with James Hughes, The Garden of Allah, Madame Curie, and his original work, Love to Mamie. Among the drafts of short stories in the next subseries is "Eben, the Hound, and the Hare," published in Gentry magazine in 1953. The drafts of speeches which follow are all concerned with Riggs' view of the theatre.
The final subseries, Writings of Others, contains several manuscript works by Ramon Naya (Enrique Gasque-Molina), a protegé of Riggs' during the late 1930s and 1940s. Also included are many typescripts of poems by George O'Neil, a typescript of a novel, The Copper Earth, by Elliot Roosevelt, and a photostat fragment of an opera, Riel, by Paul Gelrud.
Series III, Personal Papers, contains a number of items concerning Riggs' life. Among these are documents detailing the renovation of his houses in Santa Fe and on Shelter Island, a scrapbook of ideas for plays, and several annotated calendars. The Financial and Legal Papers which are housed in Series IV principally address Riggs' contractual relationships with agents and publishers.
Series V contains Photographs, chronicling the later years of Riggs' life. Found here are shots of scenes from All the Way Home and Laughter From a Cloud. Informal snapshots picture Lynn Riggs with friends such as Joan Crawford and Franchot Tone, as well as unidentified visitors to his houses in Santa Fe and on Shelter Island. A series of informal portraits features Riggs in a range of poses, most likely set in his apartment in New York around 1951.
Series VI, Printed Material, contains items collected by Riggs over several decades. Here there are a number of clippings of various subjects and many programs for productions of plays by Riggs and by other playwrights.
A number of monograph items and issues of magazines which came with this archive have been catalogued separately. The following list identifies Rigg's writings which appeared in magazines that were catalogued:
"Eben, the Hound, and the Hare" (short story) Gentry Summer, 1953
"A Hand on Mountains" and "Black Wall" (poems) Avenue April, 1934
"I Who Have Been a Soldier" (group of four poems) The Lyric Winter,
1945
"Morning Walk - Santa Fe" (poem) Palms, [1925?]
"New Song" (poem) Harper's Magazine, November, 1946
"When People Say 'Folk Drama'" The Carolina Play Book June, 1931
Dramatists, American -- Archives; Naya, Ramon; O'Neil, George, 1898-1940; Riggs, Lynn, 1899-1954; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979 ( Oklahoma!)
- Correspondence, 1927-54; Series I; 2.5; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is arranged by name of correspondent.
  - "A" general, 1933-48, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allen, Sallie and David, 1940, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Maxwell, 1931 Jun 29
  - Asher, Jerry, 1935, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Authors' League of America, 1936-48
  - "B" general, 1931-53, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baker, Paul, 1941-53, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: David O. Selznick, Box 5, folder 116
  - Bassage, Harold, 1936
  - Baylor University, 1941, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Beal, Helen
    See: Helen Craig, Box 1, folder 23
  - Beal, John, 1934-36, n.d.
  - Bel Geddes, Norman, 1936, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bentonelli, Joseph, 1931-53, n.d.
  - Blitzstein, Marc, 1939 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brice, Mary, 1928-30
  - Bynner, Witter, 1931-53 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "C" general, 1933-54, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Carharts, Peter, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Carroll, Walter, 1945-53, n.d.
  - Cerf, Bennett, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chanslor, Roy, 1934-46, n.d.
  - Charles, Lucile, 1936-37 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clark, Barrett, 1928-51, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15-19)
  - Clark, Donald, 1934, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Columbia Pictures, 1945, n.d.
  - Copland, Aaron, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Copmann, Elizabeth, 1941, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cornell University, 1953
  - Cozzens, James, 1931-36 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Craig, Helen [Helen Beal], n.d.
  - Crawford, Cheryl, 1930-37, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    See also: The Group Theatre, Inc., Box 2, folder 48
  - Crawford, Joan, 1933-44, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Crews, Judson, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes chapbook "Psalms for a Late Season"
  - Cummings, Constance, n.d.
  - Cundiff, Mattie, 1941-51, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Currie, Stu, 1953, n.d.
  - "D" general, 1931-53, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Davis, Bette, 1940, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Davis, G. D., 1936-37 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Deeter, Jasper
    See: Hedgerow Theatre, Box 2, folder 52
  - De Mille, Agnes, 1952 Jan 4
  - Dillon, George, 1931, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1939-40
  - Dramatists' Guild of the Authors' League of America, 1936-49, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Doubleday and Co., 1933-54, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "E" general, 1929-54, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Eastman, Ida Rauh, 1932-45, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "F" general, 1931-49, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Falk, Sawyer, 1934-44, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Fall, John, 1942-43
  - Farley, Morgan, 1943, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Fergusson, Erna and Harvey
  - First National Bank of Santa Fe, 1937-41 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Fishbein, Frieda, 1938-41 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Fisher, Mary, 1936
  - Foss, Lukas, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "G" general, 1934-53, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Gelrud, Paul, 1952 Mar 2 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Goldstone Agency, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Gormly, George, 1934-37
  - Grant, Marshall, 1942-45 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Green, Paul, 1929-52, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Greer, Herbert, 1937, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Grimes, Joan, 1941, 1942, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - The Group Theatre, Inc., 1932, 1936, n.d.
    See also: Cheryl Crawford, Box 1, folder 24
  - "H" general, 1930-53, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Halsey, Peg, 1944, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, II, 1953 Aug 31
    See also: Howard Reinheimer, Box 5, folder 99
  - Hansen, Paul, 1936, 1939, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Harris, Henriette, 1932-40, n.d.
  - Hedgerow Theatre, 1928-49, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - H. E. Edington-F. W. Vincent, Inc., 1934-41, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Helburn, Theresa
    See: David O. Selznick, Box 5, folder 116
    See: Theatre Guild, Inc., Box 6, folder 120
  - Henderson, Alice Corbin, 1932-34 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Henneke, Ben, 1940, n.d.
  - Hopkins, Arthur, 1930, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Horgan, Paul, 1936, 1941, n.d.
  - Hughes, Langston, 1934, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Hunter, Kermit, 1951, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Hunter, Mary, 1934-40, n.d.
  - Huston, Philip, 1937, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - "I" general, 1935-52, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - "J" general, 1936-52, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - J. H. Stevenson & Co., 1937 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Jilinsky, Andrius, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1928-44 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Johnson, Spud, 1936-51, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1930-50, n.d.
  - "K" general, 1931-52, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Kaho, Noel, 1945-53, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Kline, Herbert, 1936, 1937, n.d.
  - Knee, Ernest, 1934 Apr 26 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Knee, Gina, 1938-49, n.d.
  - Kroll, Lucy, 1948-54, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 68-69)
  - "L" general, 1932-53, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 70-71)
  - Langner, Lawrence
  - Lederer, Francis, 1934, 1936, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Leland Hayward, Inc., 1937-39 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Lesemann, Marjorie, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Lesemann, Maurice, 1934, 1944, n.d.
  - Leverton, Garrett, 1932-49, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Lewis and Fredrik Theatrical Productions, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    See also: Lucy Kroll, Box 3, folder 68
  - Limón, José, 1943-51, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Limón, Pauline, 1947 Jan 29
  - Little Theatre of Dallas, 1932-41 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Long, Haniel, n.d.
  - Lumet, Sidney, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Lunt, Alfred, 1932, n.d.
  - "M" general, 1929-53, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 80-81)
  - Mabie, E. C., 1933-48 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Machado, Gui, 1952
  - Mamoulian, Rouben, 1933 Apr 6 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Markel, Bess, 1941, n.d.
  - Marquis, Marjorie, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - May, Henry and Marjorie, 1944-45, n.d.
  - Mayer, Jerry, 1936-37, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Mayorga, Margaret, 1937, 1939, n.d.
  - Milburn, George, 1930-31 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Moross, Jerome, 1937-50, n.d.
  - Moss, Bill, 1942-45 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Muir, Jean, 1940, 1945, n.d.
  - "N" general, 1931-53, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Naya, Ramon, 1939-44, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - The New Yorker, 1944 Oct 23
    Includes typescript carbon of "Fabliau of Florida"
  - "O" general, 1937-49, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - O'Connell, Richard, 1943, 1948, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - O'Neil, George, 1927-37, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 92-94)
  - "P" general, 1930-53, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Phillips, Marion
  - Poetry; a magazine of verse, 1939-45 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Poetry Society of Texas, 1944, 1946
  - Priestley, J. B., 1947 Oct 25 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Prisk, Berneice, 1948, n.d.
  - "R" general, 1932-53, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Reed, Tom
  - Reinheimer, Howard, 1944-52 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    Includes letters from Oscar Hammerstein II
  - Riggs, Edgar, 1947 Mar 24 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Riggs, Edrye, n.d.
  - Riggs, Jerry Lee, 1949 Jun 11 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Riggs, Joe V., 1939-53, n.d.
  - Riggs, W. G., 1928-44, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Rodriguez, Moises, 1936, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Rogers, John William, 1941-42, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Roosevelt, Elliott, 1933-34 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - "S" general, 1932-52, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 106-107)
  - Samuel French, Inc., 1928-52, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 108-114)
    See also: Barrett Clark, Box 1, folder 15
    See also: Garrett Leverton, Box 3, folder 75
    See also: Series II, Box 8, folder 164
  - Saginaw Players, 1944 Apr 8 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1932 Dec 16
  - Selznick, David O., 1936-42 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    Includes letters of reference for Lynn Riggs from: Paul Baker, Marshall Grant, Theresa Helburn, Arthur Hopkins, Garrett Leverton, and Tom Reed
  - Smith, Paul, 1942-49 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Stevenson, Joe, 1937
  - Stewart, Rosalie
    See: H. E. Edington-F. W. Vincent, Inc., Box 2, folder 53
  - "T" general, 1928-51, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Texas Institute of Letters, 1940-41 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Theatre Arts, 1941, 1945
    Includes letters from Rosamond Gilder
  - Theatre Arts Books, 1949, 1953
  - Theatre Guild, Inc., 1930-51 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - The Thomas', 1943-45, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Trampler, Eleanor, 1949, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Trampler, Walter, 1944-52, n.d.
  - Trilling, Lionel, 1951 Feb 8 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Tucker, Martin, 1953
  - Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation, 1944
  - United States. Bureau of Selective Service, 1943-44, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - United States. Internal Revenue Service, 1934-37
  - United States. Office of War Information, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Universal Pictures, 1936-46
  - University of Oklahoma, 1936-52 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1941
  - University of Tulsa, 1939-49, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - "V" general, 1935, 1942, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Van Doren, Harold, 1931, 1943, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - "W" general, 1933-52, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Wallace, Richard, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Walter Wanger Productions, 1937, 1940, n.d.
  - Webster, Ann, 1933-44 (Box 6, Folder 132-134)
    Includes poem by Haniel Long
  - Western Reserve University, 1933-52, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 135)
    Includes correspondence with John F. White
  - White, Nat S. and Lou, 1951, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Wilder, Thornton, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - William Morris Agency, 1942, 1944
  - Winter, Ella
    See: Langston Hughes, Box 3, folder 56
  - Wolman, Cecil, 1936, 1944, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - Wood, Audrey, 1940
  - Yost, Margaret, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Unidentified, 1929-52 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    Includes carbons of outgoing letters from Riggs, Oct 5, 1930-Apr 15, 1952, and incoming letters dated Apr 3, 1929-Sep 4, 1952
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Baker, Paul
      - to Mr. Pearson, 1941 Oct 29 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Brandt, Joseph
      - to Joe Riggs, 1941 Oct 13 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Charles, Lucile
      - Letter introducing conference of dramatists, 1936 Oct 6 (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Clark, Barrett
      - to New York Herald Tribune, 1949 Apr 25 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - [Cundiff], Mattie
      - to Lucy Kroll, 1954 Jul 5 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Denison, Merrill
      - to Frederick Willis, 1936 Nov 26 (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Gasque, Alonso
      - to Ramon Naya, 1937-38 (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Gasque, Rosa
      - to Ramon Naya, 1937 Nov 18 (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - H. E. Edington-F. W. Vincent, Inc.
      - Internal memoranda to Rosalie Stewart, 1937 Feb (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - Kerr, John
      - to Jack McCoy, 1941 Jul 2 (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Naya, Ramon
      - to U. S. Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1937 Nov 21 (Box 7, Folder 152)
      - to Miss Thatcher, 1939 Apr 22
    - Poupeye, Camille
      - to Garrett Leverton, 1947 Nov 23 (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Rose, A. D.
      - to Ramon Naya [with key], 1941 Jan 8 (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - Theatre Guild, Inc. [Lawrence Langner]
      - to Barrett Clark, 1932 Jun 7 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Titterton, L. H. [for NBC]
      - to Audrey Wood, Liebling-Wood, 1938 Nov 5 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Walling, Frank
      - to George C. Gormly, 1935 Mar 29 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - White, John F.
      - to Nathan Kroll, 1951 Jan 19 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Unidentified
      - Includes letter to "Paul" from "B & B" and 2 unrelated "before" and "after" photographs of the interior of a church (Box 7, Folder 159)
- Writings, 1924-54; Series II; 7.25; (17 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is arranged by type of material, then alphabetically.
  - ARTICLES
    - "A Note on 'We Speak for Ourselves'"
      - Typescript, carbon, 1943 Nov (Box 8, Folder 160)
      - Printed version, The Dance Observer, 1943 Nov (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - JOURNALS
    - Santa Fe notebook (with clippings and enclosures), ca. 1924-25 (Box 8, Folder 162)
    - Journal, holograph (with clippings), 1940 Feb-Aug (Box 8, Folder 163)
    - Journal, holograph (with synopsis of "To Cheat the Winter" and letter to Samuel French, Inc. 1941 Jan 26), 1940-41 (Box 8, Folder 164)
    - Journal, holograph, 1942 Mar-May (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Journal, holograph (with notes for "The Forgotten Language," "Eben, the Hound and the Hare," and "The Novel"), 1939-52 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - NOTES
    - Baylor University lecture notes, "Drama and the Playwright,", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Baylor University teaching notes, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 168-169)
    - Notes made by Lynn Riggs while in the United States Army, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1926-51, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 171-172)
  - NOVELS
    - The Affair at Easter
      - Working notebook, 1953-54 (Box 9, Folder 173)
      - Part I, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1953 Jul (Box 9, Folder 174)
      - Part I, typescript, [1954?] (Box 9, Folder 175)
      - Parts I and II, draft, typescript, corrected, [1954?] (Box 9, Folder 176)
      - Parts I-III, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 177)
      - Part II, draft fragments, typescript carbon, corrected, 1953 Jul-Aug (Box 10, Folder 178)
      - Part II, draft fragments, typescript, [1953?] (Box 10, Folder 179)
      - Part III, draft fragments, typescript, corrected, [1954?] (Box 10, Folder 180)
      - Part III, draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1954 Mar-Apr (Box 10, Folder 181)
      - Parts III-IV, draft, typescript, corrected, 1954 Mar 11 (Box 10, Folder 182)